各位亲朋好友 今天大家齐聚一堂
Friends,family,we're gathered to celebrate...
庆祝罗斯与艾蜜莉缔结良缘
...the joyous union of Ross and Emily.
罗斯，请跟我复述
Now,Ross,repeat after me.
我，罗斯… 我，罗斯…
"l,Ross."I,Ross.
娶你，艾蜜莉… 娶你，瑞秋…
"Take thee,Emily."Take thee,Rachel.
艾蜜莉
Emily
要继续吗？
Shall I go on?
他说瑞秋对不对？ 我要过去吗？
He said,"Rachel," right?Do you think I should go up there?
请继续
Yes. Yes. Do go on.
我们最好重新来过
I think we'd better start again.
罗斯，请你跟着我说
Repeat after me.
我，罗斯… 我，罗斯…
"l,Ross."I,Ross.
娶你，艾…蜜…莉…
"Take thee,Emily."
娶你，艾蜜莉…
Take thee,Emily.
就好像还有别人似的
Like there'd be anybody else.
成为我的合法发妻 无论贫病，至死不渝
"As my lawfully wedded wife,in sickness and in health...till death parts us."
As my lawfully wedded wife,in sickness and in health...until death parts us.
我愿意，艾蜜莉
Really,I do. Emily.
请给我婚戒
Do you have the rings?
艾蜜莉，为罗斯戴上戒指 象征你永远爱他
Place this ring on Ross' finger...as a symbol of your bond everlasting.
罗斯，为艾蜜莉戴上戒指 代表你俩白头偕老
Ross,place this ring on Emily's hand as a symbol of the love that encircles you forever.
我很乐意
Happy to.
罗斯与艾蜜莉已经宣誓
They have made their declarations...
我很荣幸宣布他们成为夫妻
...and it gives me great pleasure to declare them husband and wife.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
这比他娶同性恋那次更糟糕
This is worse than when he married the lesbian.
保持微笑
Just keep smiling.
好
Okey
进行得真顺利
Well,that went well.
他没开枪杀死她就不错了
It could've been worse. He could've shot her.
刚才太有趣了，对吧
That was pretty funny,wasn't it?
本集播出：“罗斯说了‘瑞秋’之后”
The One After Ross Says "Rachel"
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
你搞砸所有事情 我丢死人了
You spoiled everything! It's a nightmare!
我的亲朋好友都在场 我以后拿什么脸见人？
My friends and family are out there! How can I face them?
你怎么做得出来？
How can you do this to me？
无论如何 我们都吃得到蛋糕吧？
No matter what happens with them...we still get cake,right?
没关系，亲爱的，你慢慢来 我在外面等你
That's all right. You take your time. I'll be right out here.
她要补妆
She's just fixing her makeup.
我恨你
I hate you!
我也爱你
And I love you!
罗斯，你偏挑这个时候 说错名字
A bad time to say the wrong name,huh?
你说得对，谢了，老爸
That's true. Thanks,Dad.
大家应该跳舞啊
People should be dancing.
这是婚宴，乔伊，跳舞啊
This is a party! Come on!Joey! Dance!
华森府邸
Yes,Waltham lnteriors.
你好，我是罗斯盖勒的医生 佛兰姬
This is Ross Geller's personal physician,Dr. Filangie.
谁？
Who?
我发现罗斯忘了吃错乱药
I discovered that Ross forgot to take his brain medicine.
他这人不吃药 就有可能讲错女人的名字
Without it,in the brain of Ross...women's names are interchangeable.
这完全不能怪他
Through no fault of his own.
上帝啊，是你菲比
Oh,my God! Phoebe.
我不是菲比，是佛兰姬医生
No,not Phoebe. Dr. Filangie.
你也错乱了
Oh,no! You have it too!
什么臭女人敢挂医生的电话？
What kind of bitch hangs up on a doctor?
嘿 嗨
-Hi！ -Hey
希望你别误会
I hope you don't take this the wrong way...
我知道我们今晚约了要见面
...but I know we had plans to meet up tonight.
但是我担心以后做不成朋友
I'm worried about what it might do to our friendship.
我明白
I know.
我们怎么这么不小心 还不小心了七次
-How could we have let this happen? -Seven times!
你知道，我们人在国外
You know,look. We were away.
又是浪漫的异乡
In a foreign,romantic country.
都怪伦敦不好
I blame London.
坏伦敦
Bad London!
既然我们还在伦敦 就可以继续，对不对？
So look...while we're still in London,we can keep doing it,right?
看来我们别无选择
Well,I don't see that we have a choice.
但是我们回去就得停止
But when we're back home,we don't do it.
只有这里例外
Only here.
我看到楼下有酒窖
You know,I saw a wine cellar downstairs.
我两分钟后下去找你 好
I'll meet you there in two minutes.
我有事情要问你 现在？
Mon? I gotta ask you something.Now?
罗斯刚刚说出我的名字 我不能假装没听到吧
Ross said my name. I can't just pretend it didn't happen.
我不知道
I don't know.
莫妮卡，我该怎么办？
Monica,what should I do?
做正确的事就行了
Just do the right thing.
什么？
What?
听天由命，努力争取 不要死心眼
Tow the line! Thread the needle! Think outside the box!
等等，我要问罗斯 他是什么意思
I'll talk to Ross about what he thinks it meant.
瑞秋，不要，他已经结婚了
Wait! Rachel,no.He's married.Married.
要是你还不懂，我也没法帮到你
If you don't realize that,I can't help you.
你说得对，你帮不了我
Okay. You're right.You're right. You can't help me.
杰克，这是我们的错吗？ 没把小孩教好？
Jack,is it all our fault? Were we bad parents?
对
Yes
没地方坐还叫人吃牛排 这要怎么搞？
Who serves steak when there's no place to sit?How are you supposed to eat this?
怎么了
Hey,what's up?
下首音乐跟我跳舞好吗？
You and me,next dance?
抱歉，我只有喝醉才跳舞
Sorry,dear,I only dance when I'm drunk.
你想喝点什么？
Want me to get you something?
你跑哪去了？不是约在酒窖吗？
Where were you？We were supposed to meet in the wine cellar？
算了，当我没说
-Forget it. That's off.
为什么？
-Why?
两分钟后…为各位介绍酒窖
The next tour of the wine cellar will commence in two minutes.
乔伊，你搞什么？ 你答应菲比等她生完才吃肉
Joey,what are you doing?You promised,no meat till Phoebe has the babies.
既然我们在国外就不算
We're in another country,so it doesn't count.
那倒是 他说得对
-True. -He's got a point.
很抱歉，事情竟然出状况
I'm sorry things aren't working out.
的确不太妙，不过会解决的
It could be better. It'll be okay,right?
当然，她不会放在心上
Oh,yeah! Of course. She'll get over this.
你脱口说出我的名字又如何
So you said my name.
不过是因为你刚好看到我
You just said it because you saw me there.
如果你是看到怪胎
If you'd seen a circus freak,you would've said:
也会说：我娶你，怪胎
"l take thee,Circus Freak."
根本没有别的意思 只是无心之过
It didn't mean anything. It's a mistake.
没有别的意思，对吧？
It didn't mean anything. Right?
当然没有
Oh,no! Of course it didn't mean anything.
但是我明白艾蜜莉为何误会 因为这刚好是你的名字
I can understand why Emily thought it meant something...because it was you.
其实没有意义，真的没有
But it absolutely didn't. It didn't! It didn't!
罗斯，乐队正在 等你跟艾蜜莉开舞
The band's ready for your first dance with Emily.
噢，乐队准备好了
Oh! The band's ready!
我们最好听乐队的话 我才不在乎那愚蠢的乐队！
We've got to do what the band says. I don't care about the stupid band!
你口水喷到我了
You spit on me,man!
对不起
I'm sorry.
艾蜜莉也进去太久了吧
Emily is taking kind of a long time.
我结婚时也躲在厕所不出来 不过那是因为我要撬开窗户
When I locked myself up at my wedding I was trying to pop the window out of the frame.
是啊
Right
我一心想要逃出去
Get the hell out of there. You know?
艾蜜莉，艾蜜莉
Emily，Emily
我要进去了
I'm coming in!
你看，同一招
Oh,look at that. Same thing.
如果我中途大喊“好耶” 你就当作没听到
In the middle of everything,if I scream,"Yippee!" just ignore me.
天啊，瑞秋，嗨，瑞秋
-Oh,my God! Rachel! -Oh,hello,Rachel.
罗斯叫出我的名字，是我的名字
Ross said my name.Okay? My name!
他会说成我的名字 表示他还爱我
Ross said my name up there.That obviously means he still loves me!
不信就算了，我绝对没误会
Don't believe me. I know I'm right.
你们要不要下楼喝一杯？
Do you guys want to go and get a drink?
好啊，不过我们要先换衣服
Yes,we do.But we have to change first.
对，我想换衣服
Yes,I want to change.
你先下去占位子 我们五分钟就下去
-Go get a table. -We'll only be five minutes.
十五分钟吧
Fifteen minutes.
好
Okey
喂，菲比啊，是菲比
Oh,Phoebe! It's Phoebe!
是吗？ 太好了
-Oh,hey,hey. -Oh,great.
嗨
Hi
发生什么事了？
So,what happened?
罗斯说成我的名字
Well,Ross said my name.
我知道，不过他是无心的
But I don't think that means anything.
菲比，我们冷静客观想想看
Let's look at this objectively.
他从九年级就暗恋我对吧
Ninth grade,right?
那时就疯狂迷上我
The obsession starts.
那年暑假 他头一次看我穿两件式
Then he sees me in a two-piece for the first time.
更是不可自拔爱上我
His obsession begins to grow,right?
去我房间换衣服好了
Why don't we go change in my room?
可是我的衣服在…
My clothes are....
你看起来真是… 没时间废话了
Wow,you look…No time for that.
老兄，让我进去，我有女伴
Hey,dude! Let me in! I got a girl out here!
我也有
I got a girl in here!
才怪，我看到你跟莫妮卡进去
No,you don't. I saw you go in with Monica.
我们在里面聊天
Well,we're hanging out.
你说我们两对谁有机会做爱？我还是你？
Which one of us will be having sex in there? Me or you?
看来我只能说是你了
I suppose I would have to say you.
可是我们正在看电视
-What if we're watching a movie?
没错，我们付费了 正在看“我的巨人”
-Which we are!And we've paid for it.It's My Giant.
“我的巨人”？我爱死那部片
My Giant?I love that movie!
你确定这样好吗？
Think this is okay?
反正罗斯跟艾蜜莉也用不到
Well,Ross and Emily aren't going to use it.
这里好漂亮
Oh,it's so beautiful!
可是我总觉得不太妥当
I don't feel right about this.
莫…听我说
Oh Mon-Mon-Mon-Mon-look，
这是蜜月套房 这间房期待着性
This is the honeymoon suite.The room expects sex.
如果没有，这间房一定很失望
The room would be disappointed if it didn't get sex.
在其他蜜月套房面前抬不起头
All the other honeymoon suites would think it was a loser.
好吧 那好
Okey，Okey
艾蜜莉？
Emily？
没有，没在这下面
Nope! Not under here!
你还没找到她？
-You didn't find her?
我到处都找不到
-I've looked everywhere.
你一定漏掉什么地方 否则早就找到了
You couldn't have,or you would've found her.
你应该继续找
-Keep looking!
大概再找个30分钟
-Yeah! For about 30 minutes?
或是45分钟
Or 45?
45分钟可以找到两次了
In 45 minutes,you could find her twice.
不了，她一定也找不到我 因为我跑来跑去
For all I know,she's trying to find me but couldn't,because I kept moving.
从现在开始我不动了 我就待在这里
From now on,I'm staying in one place.Right here.
时间晚了 我们要走了
-It's getting late. -We're going to go.
你们在这儿待一会儿如何？
Do you guys mind staying here for a while?
可是我们明天一早 就要搭飞机回纽约（与“捕捉飞机”同音）
We've got to get up early and catch that plane.
是的那班飞机很大
Yeah,it's a very large plane.
那就算了
That's cool.
不过我们还是陪你一会
But we'll stay here with you.
谢了
Thanks,guys!
我很感激你们的好意 但是你也不用摸我屁股
I really appreciate this,but you don't need to rub my butt.
我们一小时后就要回纽约了
We have to leave in an hour.
我知道
I know.
我一直在看那扇门 隔音效果似乎很好
I've been looking at those doors.They look pretty soundproof,don't you think?
不行，你疯了
We can't do that. That's insane.
第一，他可能醒来 第二，管他的
I mean,A,he could wake up. And B,you know...Let's go for it.
艾蜜莉？艾蜜莉…
Emily？Emily
艾蜜莉
Emily
不是她
Nope.
她没跟我们在一块儿 我们来拿她的东西
-She's not with us. -We've come for her things.
她在哪里？
Where is she?
她躲起来了，因为她很丢脸 这辈子都不想再见到你
She's in hiding. She's humiliated. She doesn't want to see you again.
我们很伤心你们两个闹成这样 猴子
We're very sad that it didn't work out between you and Emily,monkey.
不过你实在是秀色可餐
But I think you're absolutely delicious!
抱歉，我人还站在这里
Excuse me,I'm standing right here.
是啊，阴魂不散
Oh,yes.There you are.
大家动作快点，外面还有一车
Hurry up! Get some! There's a whole cart outside.
再见了，盖勒
Goodbye,Geller.
等一下…
Now,hold on. Hold on.
你的女儿跟我今晚预定去度蜜月
Your daughter and I are supposed to leave tonight for our honeymoon.
请你们转告她，我会去机场 我希望她也会去
Tell her I'll be at that airport,and I hope she will too.
我是说成瑞秋的名字 但这只是无心之过
I said Rachel's name,but it didn't mean anything.
她不过是我的朋友
She's just a friend and that's all.
就这样，请转告艾蜜莉 我爱她
That‘s all！Now just tell Emily that I love her and...
我只想跟她共度余生
...that I can't imagine spending my life with anyone else.
请保证你们一定会转告她
Please,promise me that you'll tell her that.
我会告诉她，走吧，臭婆娘
All right,I'll tell her.Come on,bugger face!
打电话给我
Call me.
你也一天到晚待在厕所 怎么就不会从窗户滚蛋
You spend your life in the bathroom. Why do you never go out the window?
或许我们不再上床才对
Maybe it's best we never got to do it again.
否则那晚就不特别了
Yeah,it kind of makes that one night special.
理论上而言，我们还在海外
Technically,we still are over international waters.
我去洗手间，待会来找我？
I'm going to the bathroom. Maybe I'll see you there?
好
Okey
我可以问个问题吗？
Can I ask you something?
不行
No
我昨晚跟费丽西蒂 一起看“我的巨人”
Felicity and I watched My Giant. And I thought:
我心想：自己永远不可能 演得跟那个巨人一样棒
"I'll never be as good an actor as that giant."
我想当演员是否只是痴心妄想
Do you think I'm wasting my life with this acting thing?
不是
No
那个巨人大概比我小五岁 我有办法跟他一样优秀吗？
The giant's five years younger than me.You think I'll ever get there?
会的
Yes
谢了
-Thanks,man.
没关系
-Okay,man.
但是他比我高好多啊
But what about how much taller he is than me?
我现在已经不可能再长高
I mean,there's no way I can make myself taller now.
以后科学怎么发展我不知道
Who knows what science will come up with in the future...
如果我死时只是一个 身高平庸的小人物呢？
...but what if I die an unsuccessful,regular-size man?
莫妮卡，你厕所上了半个小时
You've been in the bathroom for a half-hour.
我知道
I know!
你也吃了牛肉？
Had the beef tips,huh?
嗨 嗨
Hi Hi
你吃过肉了
You ate meat!
你跟人做爱
You had sex!
我们才没有
No,we didn't.
我知道你没有 我说的是莫妮卡
I know you didn't. I was talking about Monica.
菲比，我才没跟人做爱
I did not have sex.
怀孕害我灵感不准
This pregnancy is throwing me all off
而且还变得胖嘟嘟
and making me fat.
我要去跟小鸡小鸭打招呼
-I'll say hi to the chick and duck.
我也去
-Me too!
你何必去？ 你不是一直都去喂它们的嘛？
Why would you need to? You've been feeding them.
没错，我回家好了
Oh,right. Maybe I'll just go home.
只剩下我们两个
We certainly are alone.
幸好我们说好回纽约就不行
Good thing we have that "not New York" rule.
没错
Okey
既然你说到这个
Listen,since we're on that subject...
我想告诉你…
...I just wanted to tell you that....
当时我在伦敦心情很不好
I was going through a hard time in London...
因为哥哥结婚 别人还把我认作他妈
...with my brother getting married and that guy thinking I was Ross' mother.
我知道
Right
那晚对我来说意义非凡
Well,anyway,I just....That night meant a lot to me.
我的意思是…我要谢谢你
And I'm trying to say thanks.
我那天也不是随便上床
You know,that night meant a lot to me too.
并不是因为我受到逼迫
It wasn't because I was in a bad place or anything.
我很重视那晚是因为 你很辣
It just meant a lot because you're really hot.
这样说可以吗？
Is that okay?
没关系
That's okay.
而且我也很帅
And I'm cute too?
而且你也很帅 谢谢
And you're cute too!Thank you.
我要去整理行李了 好
All right,I gotta go unpack.
再见
Bye
我时差还没调回来 这表示我还在伦敦吧
I'm still on London time. Does that count?
没错 太好了
-Oh,that counts! -Oh,good!
瑞秋…
Rachel
嗨
Hi
你怎么会在这里？
What are you doing here?
我在等候补机位回纽约
I've been on standby for a flight home for hours.
你还没等到艾蜜莉？
So no sign of Emily?
还没
Not yet.
你是几点的飞机？
When do you have to leave?
最后一次呼叫 前往雅典的1066班机
This is the last call for flight 1066 to Athens.The last call.
就快了 是啊
Pretty soon,I guess.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我不明白她怎么可以这么做？
I don't understand.How could she do this?
我是不是白痴？ 竟然以为她会来
Am I a complete idiot for thinking she'd actually show up?
你不是白痴，罗斯
You're not an idiot,Ross.
你只是爱得无可救药
You're a guy very much in love.
一样
Same difference.
搭乘1066班机 前往雅典的旅客请登机
All passengers for flight 1066 to Athens should now be onboard.
听到了
I get it!
完了
Well,that's that.
不，你应该去
No,you know what?I think you should go.
什么？ 对
What？Ya！
你应该自己去 到遥远的地方想个清楚
I think you should go...by yourself. Get some distance.Clear your head.
这对你一定有好处
It would be really good.
我不知道…
I don't know.
罗斯，你应该要去
Come on. It would be really good for you.
没错，我应该去 对
I could do that.
真不敢相信，她
I can't even believe her.
知道吗？我决定去了
You know what? I am going to go.
很好 有何不可呢？
-Good. -Why not?
对 对不对？
-Right?
没错
-Right.
谢了
Thanks.
我们纽约见了 希望我搭得上飞机
I'll see you back at home.If I ever get a flight out of here.
其实…算了 怎么了？
Hey，W…What? Wait,what?
不如你也一起来 反正我有两张机票
Why don't you come?I mean,I have two tickets. Why not?
不太好吧？真的吗？
Well,I don't know,Ross. Really?
是啊，一定很好玩 你可以躺在海滩上
Yeah. It'd be great. I mean,you can....You can lay on the beach
我可以哭诉婚姻失败 你看我多好笑啊
...and I can cry over my failed marriage.You see how I make jokes?
真的，我需要有朋友陪我
Really. I mean....I could use a friend.
好吧，也许
Oh,wow. Maybe.
我可以陪你去
Yes,I can do that!
好 好
Okay！Okay！
太好了 是啊
-Cool. -All right,cool.
走吧，拿去
All right！Come on
我们这就去希腊
Okay,we're going to Greece.
我忘了拿外套 等一下
I forgot my jacket!Oh，wait-
你叫他们等一下
Well,you tell them to wait.
等一下
Wait! Wait!
艾蜜莉
Emily
不是啦…别走，艾蜜莉
Oh no-no-no! Oh-no! No! No! Emily!
我要美露红酒
I'll have a glass of Merlot...
这位要气泡白酒
...and he'll have a wine spritzer.
你们看，机场在动
Look! The airport's moving.
飞机在动吗？
Are we moving?
飞机在动吗？为什么？
Are we? Why are we moving?
机长知道飞机在动吗？
Does the captain know that we're moving?
我的天啊
Oh,my gosh!